<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<index version="1" name="TLM JSFX">
  <category name="Effects">
    <reapack name="Retro Codec Suite (TLM)" type="effect" desc="Vintage gaming console audio compression emulation">
      <metadata>
        <description><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 Tahoma;}
{\colortbl;\red0\green0\blue0;}
\f0\fs16
Authentic emulation of vintage gaming console audio compression formats. Transform your audio with the signature sound of classic gaming hardware.
Features:
• 4 Codec Types: N64 VADPCM, IMA ADPCM, 4-bit PCM, PSX ADPCM
• Period-accurate sample rates (11-44kHz) and bit depths (4-24 bit)
• Saturation, artifacts intensity, dry/wet mix, and output gain controls
• Optional anti-aliasing pre-filter and lo-fi character filter
• Professional GUI with visual feedback and parameter controls
Codec Types:
• N64 VADPCM - Nintendo 64's Vector-Adaptive Differential PCM (Ocarina of Time, GoldenEye)
• IMA ADPCM - Interactive Multimedia Association standard for CD-ROM games
• 4-bit PCM - Aggressive lo-fi digital artifacts
• PSX ADPCM - PlayStation 1's format (Final Fantasy VII, Metal Gear Solid)
Controls:
• Codec Type - Select compression format
• Sample Rate - 11kHz, 16kHz, 22kHz, 32kHz (default), 44kHz
• Bit Depth - 4-bit, 8-bit, 16-bit (default), 24-bit
• Saturation - Soft saturation for harmonic warmth
• Artifacts - Control compression artifact intensity
• Mix - Blend processed and dry signals
• Output - Master output level (±12dB range, 0dB default)
• Anti-Aliasing - Pre-filter to reduce aliasing
• Lo-Fi Filter - Character filter matching target sample rate
Perfect for chiptune music, lo-fi beats, retro game soundtracks, and experimental sound design.
}]]></description>
        <screenshot>https://i.imgur.com/55v0koi.png</screenshot>
      </metadata>
      <version name="7.1" author="Thomas LeRoy Meier" time="2025-01-18T00:00:00Z">
        <source>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ThomasListens/TLM-JSFX/main/RetroCodecSuite.jsfx</source>
        <changelog><![CDATA[
v7.1 - Initial Release
• 4 authentic codec emulations: N64 VADPCM, IMA ADPCM, 4-bit PCM, PSX ADPCM
• Period-accurate sample rates (11-44kHz) and bit depths (4-24 bit)
• Stable artifact processing with normalized gain coefficients
• Professional custom GUI with dropdown codec selector
• Visual feedback with stepped sliders for sample rate and bit depth
• Double-click any slider to reset to default value
• Optional anti-aliasing and lo-fi filters for authentic retro character
• Output defaults to 0dB with ±12dB range for gain staging
• CPU-efficient real-time processing with parameter smoothing
        ]]></changelog>
      </version>
    </reapack>
    <reapack name="Seed Delay (TLM)" type="effect" desc="Multi-tap delay with creative algorithms">
      <metadata>
        <description><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 Tahoma;}
{\colortbl;\red0\green0\blue0;}
\f0\fs16
A multi-tap delay plugin featuring creative, musical, and organically-inspired algorithms to produce 12 unique delay timings.
Features:
• 12-tap delay matrix with individual control over each tap
• 8 unique timing algorithms inspired by nature, music theory, and mathematics
• Per-tap volume and pan controls with visual envelope editing
• Intuitive grid-based interface
• Enhanced feedback range with organic "jungle" character processing
• Anti-aliased harmonic generation for clean high-frequency response
Algorithms:
• Seed Random - Generates unpredictable, organic delay patterns
• Quantum Shuffle - Timing variations based on quantum probability concepts
• Perlin Noise - Smooth, natural variations using noise algorithms
• Spiral Wave - Creates spiraling, evolving delay patterns
• Chromatic - Delays based on chromatic scale intervals
• Harmonic - Musically-consonant delays following harmonic series
• Fibonacci - Nature-inspired timing using the golden ratio
• L-System - Fractal-based patterns for complex rhythms (used to model plant growth)
Controls:
• Click any square to enable/disable individual taps
• Click VOL/PAN controls to adjust
• Shift-click to enable/disable modulation
• Ctrl-click to reset to default
• Click and drag to draw envelopes
}]]></description>
        <screenshot>https://i.imgur.com/kbfxQ4Y.png</screenshot>
      </metadata>
      <version name="1.1" author="Thomas LeRoy Meier" time="2024-12-21T18:00:00Z">
        <source>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ThomasListens/TLM-JSFX/main/SeedDelay.jsfx</source>
        <changelog><![CDATA[
v1.1 - Enhanced Feedback & Jungle Aesthetics
• Extended feedback range for more musical buildup without runaway
• Added organic "jungle" character processing with frequency-balanced harmonics
• Improved anti-aliasing protection prevents digital artifacts
• Enhanced high-frequency damping eliminates squealing at high feedback
• Subtle sub-harmonic generation adds rich low-end character above 90%
• More stable feedback scaling across all tap configurations
• Refined S-curve mapping provides better control in upper feedback ranges (75-100%)
• Gentle musical enhancement that emerges progressively with feedback level
• Maintains all original sweet spots while expanding creative possibilities
        ]]></changelog>
      </version>
    </reapack>
  </category>
  <category name="Utility">
    <reapack name="Tap Timing Utility (TLM)" type="effect" desc="Timing measurement tool">
      <metadata>
        <description><![CDATA[{\rtf1\ansi
{\fonttbl\f0\fnil\fcharset0 Tahoma;}
{\colortbl;\red0\green0\blue0;}
\f0\fs16
A timing measurement plugin for REAPER that helps you set delays and time-based effects "by hand" using your mouse or keyboard.
Features:
• Measures intervals between clicks with millisecond accuracy
• Real-time conversion to Hz, ms, and samples at current sample rate
• Tempo-aware beat division calculations
• Audio click feedback for rhythmic accuracy
• History tracking of recent measurements
• Both mouse and MIDI input modes
Use Cases:
• Setting delay times by tapping along with music
• Finding the tempo of audio material
• Calculating LFO rates and modulation speeds
• Measuring rhythmic intervals for precise timing
Usage:
1. Choose input mode (Mouse or MIDI)
2. Click the main button or play MIDI notes to mark timing points
3. View instant conversion to useful time formats
4. Use measurements to dial in delay times
}]]></description>
        <screenshot>https://i.imgur.com/xSkC0bt.png</screenshot>
      </metadata>
      <version name="1.0" author="Thomas LeRoy Meier" time="2024-01-01T00:00:00Z">
        <source>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ThomasListens/TLM-JSFX/main/TapTimingUtility.jsfx</source>
      </version>
    </reapack>
  </category>
</index>